http://www.tmp.com/privacy/

Effective Date: October 2, 2018
TMP Worldwide Advertising & Communications, LLC (“TMP Worldwide”) is committed to respecting the privacy of those who visit this site. Any online data collection from emails and forms submitted by you will only be used in the normal course of business to help us contact you and provide solutions to your challenges. This privacy policy describes how TMP Worldwide collects and uses any personal information you may provide on our web site, www.tmp.com,and via TMP Worldwide's TalentBrew Platform. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the client has engaged TMP Worldwide. Information being gathered via the TalentBrew Platform may also be subject to the privacy policy of the individual client, which may be accessed directly from the site maintained on such client’s behalf.
Privacy Shield Certification
To facilitate our operations, we may transfer, store and process your personal information in jurisdictions other than where you live, including in the United States.
Laws in these countries may differ from the laws applicable to your country of residence.
For instance, if you are a European Economic Area (EEA) data subject and your personal information is shared with our affiliates, partners, or third-party service providers acting on our behalf outside of the EEA, then it is done so pursuant to necessary means to ensure an adequate level of protection.
TMP Worldwide and its affiliates adhere to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework TMP Worldwide has certified its compliance therewith. TMP Worldwide is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, respectively, in reliance on each Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List at https://www.privacyshield.gov/list.
TMP Worldwide is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under each Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. TMP Worldwide complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.
With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, TMP Worldwide is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, TMP Worldwide may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request.
Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome,you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.
Information Collection and Use
We may collect the following personal information from you:
Contact Information such as name, email address, mailing address, phone number
Unique Identifiers such as user name, account number, password
Information about your business such as company name, company size, business type, etc.
We use this information to do one or more of the following:
Assess the needs of your business to determine suitable products
Send you requested product or service information
Respond to customer service requests
Administer your account
Send you a newsletter and marketing communications
Respond to your questions and concerns
Improve our web site and marketing efforts
Conduct research and analysis
Enable you to post your resume, search job postings, and contact or be contacted by prospective employers
Information Sharing
We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties. If you do not want us to share your personal information with these companies, contact our Customer Support at tbsupport@tmp.com.
Service Providers - We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities like offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.
Some of our pages utilize framing techniques to serve content to / from our partners while preserving the look and feel of our site. Please be aware that you are providing your personal information to these third parties and not to www.tmp.com.
Legal Disclaimer – We may also disclose your personal information; (i) as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process; (ii) when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to (a) protect our rights, (b) protect your safety or the safety of others, (c) investigate fraud or (d) respond to a government request; or (iii) to any other party with your consent.
If TMP Worldwide is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.
Information Related to Data Collected through the TalentBrew Platform
TMP Worldwide collects information under the direction of its clients, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes.
Choice
We collect information for our clients. If you are an applicant or potential applicant for employment by one of our clients or have otherwise requested to receive information from one of our clients and would no longer like to be contacted by that client, please contact directly the client with which you interact via the address provided by the client, in its privacy policy or otherwise.
Service Provider, Sub-Processors/Onward Transfer
We may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the provisions in this Policy regarding notice and choice and the service agreements with our Clients.
Access to Data Controlled by our Clients
We have no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data we process on behalf of our clients. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his query to our client (the data controller). If the client requests us to remove the data, we will respond to their request within thirty (30) days.
Data Retention
We will retain personal data we process on behalf of our clients for as long as needed to provide services to our client. We will retain and use this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
User Access and Choice
Upon request, TMP Worldwide will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your personal information. You have the right to amend or update inaccurate or incomplete personal information, request deletion of your personal information, or request that we no longer use it. If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend, delete, or deactivate it by making the change on our member information page or by emailing our Customer Support at tbsupport@tmp.com. We will respond to your request to access personal information within thirty (30) days.
We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements or as otherwise provided in the privacy policy of our client on whose behalf your information was provided.
Opt-out Preferences - If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails or accessing the email preferences in your account settings page.
Tracking Technologies / Cookies
Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags, scripts or similar technologies are used by TMP Worldwide and our marketing partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.
We use cookies for site tracking, remembering feature preferences and related purposes. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.
As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.
We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users'; movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.
We do not link this automatically-collected data to personal information.
Behavioral Targeting / Re-Targeting
We partner with one or more third parties either to display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partners may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish not to have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking here (or if located in the European Union click here.) Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.
Security
The security of your personal information submitted on the web and through the TalentBrew platform is important to us. When you enter sensitive information such as account passwords on forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).
We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our web site, please contact us at secure@tmp.com.
Additional Information
Links to 3rd Party Sites - Our site includes links to other web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of TMP Worldwide. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any web site you visit.
Social Media Widgets - Our web site includes social media features, such as the Facebook Like button and widgets, such as the ShareThis button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. Use of these features may allow us to collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and to set cookie to enable these features to function properly. Social media features and widgets are hosted either by a third party or directly on our web site. Your interaction with any of these features is governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.
Any time you post on our blog please be aware that you are posting using a third party application and we have no access or control over this information. To request removal of your personal information from our blog, you can either log into the third party application and remove your comment or you can contact the appropriate third party application. Your interaction with these features is governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.
Changes To This Policy - We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email or by means of a notice on this site. We encourage you periodically to review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.
Contact Us
If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact us on the information below.
